GOURAV JHA

Resume Objective

Experienced in Software devlopment with excellent leadership and interpersonal skills. Seeking for the position of Software developer at repute industries which working in ., offering 1+ years hands-on experience utilizing statistical modeling and machine learning techniques. Coming with proficiency in python, C and C++

Professional Experiences

Scientech Technology Pvt Ltd (Research Engineer) (July 2021 - June 2022), Indore, M.P.

- **Weather monitoring system**: Gather sensor data from different sensors and upload it to local database using Thingspeak, Mqtt and IOT.
- **Smart AI System**: Working on machine learning libraries like opency, tensorflow Matplotlib and openvino, Integrate embedded hardware such as temperature and humidity sensor, pressure sensor and rain sensor
- Programming languages: C++17 (9 months), C (1 year), python3 (6 Months), SQL (6 Months).

Internship

Signal and Communication Training School, BSF Tigri, Delhi (05-06-2019 to 15-07-19)

- Working on 8051 and AVR controller interfacing LCD display and sensors.
- Circuit Designing circuit designing software Proteus and eagle PCB.
- Interfacing of LIDAR senor wit Jetson NANO and raspberry pi

RISC-V based Soc Design UsingOpen Source (05 -06-2020 to 27-07-2020)

 Designing of RISC-V based Low power Current comparator with hysteresis using open-source tools like OPENRAM, MAGIC ,GRAYWOLF, NETGEN and NGSPICE

Projects

Designing and Controlling of Differential-Drive Robot (ROS) (2020) - Completed: Design Differential-Drive Robot from scratch and design an URDF model of robot ot simulator. Drive robot in fixed RViz map for Autonomous localization and

Loan Prediction using linear regression (2021) – Completed:. Using open source data available on kaggle. The model demonstrates how to predict loan credibility for a person on the basis of employment status, education and dependencies and etc.

Sound Wave Based Fire Extinguisher (2021) – Completed : As a part of final year project our objective is to design and develop of fire extinguisher with which extinguishes fireworking principal of sound waves. Here idea to cut the supply of fire either fuel,Oxygen, or heat.

Object Detection Using Yolo (2022) -- YOLO (you only learn onces) is an NN algorithm that uses neural nets to provide real-time object detection. This project used to predict real time data using logitech camera and classifies them into categories in excel sheet.

Hand written gesture recognition (2022) – Completed : To predict the hand character using tensorflow library and MNIST dataset and implement model on called raspberry pi.

Barcode Detection(2022) – Completed : implement machine learning algorithm to detect information in barcode and incert information to barcode using image processing.

Self-Driving Bicycle (2022) - Focused on model-based design for The Task of the project to use the Sensor data (provided while driving along the path. Testing of algorithm Simulator environment ROS(Gazebo).

Hobbies

- Playing Basketball, Football, pool
- Reading Books Specially frictions and Documentaries.
- Always ready to explore new places especially historical.
- Data Science and robotics enthusiastic

gouravjha7@gmail.com

7909340096

TCP Tekanpur, Near BSF Campus, Gwalior, M.P

in www.linkedin.com/in/gouravjha7

Skills

- FrameWorks: Scikit-learn, pandas , Pyspark, Hadoop, Opency,ROS, tensorflow/Keras, NLP, Pytorch, and H2O
- Cloud: AWS and Azure
- programming: Python, Mysql, mongoDB, Data Structure,
 Algorithms, Embedded C, C/C++.

Education

- Rustamji Institute of Technology
 <u>Tekanpur, Gwalior.</u>

 B. Tech: Electronics and Comm.
 Graduated with 7.6 CGPA upto 8th
 Sem (2017 to 2021)
- Vivekananda Higher Secondary
 School Class 12th: (Mathematics with Science)
 Completed senior High School with 50%(2017)
- BSF Sensor Secondary School <u>Compl</u>eted class 10th with 56 CGPA (2014)

Certifications

- Building Arduino robot and devices.
- Control of Mobile Robots. (Coursera)
- Computer vision objects detection with *OpenCV* and *Python*. (Coursera)
- Introduction of TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence and Machine learning. (Coursera)
- Introduction of *Git* and *GitHub*.
- Data Structure. (Coursera)
- RISC-V based Soc Design Using Open Source. (VSD-Online)
- MATLAB Training (LinkedIn)
- Introduction to tensorflow, AI, ML and Deep learning (coursera)

Personal Detail

Date of Birth: Nov, 8th 1997

Gender : Male

Languages : English, Hindi